Guide to the Ralph W. Tyler Papers 1932-1988
University of Chicago Library
- Series IV: Writings by Tyler
  - Subseries 3: Books, Pamphlets, and Papers
    - 1960, "The Behavioral Scientist Looks at the Purposes of Science-Teaching." In Rethinking Science Education "Conclusion." [Summary remarks on trends and continuities in research on colleges and students.] In The American College and Student Personality; A Survey of Research Progress and Problems "Conducting Classes to Optimize Learning." In Achieve Learning Objectives "The Contribution of the Behavioral Sciences to Educational Research." In First Annual Phi Delta Kappa Symposium on Educational Research "Educational Objectives of American Democracy." In The Nation's Children. Vol. 2; Development and Education Foreword to Patterns of Professional Education Foreword to Undergraduate Education for Social Welfare "How Can Research Help Public School Leaders Improve Education for Responsible Citizenship?" In Education for World Leadership "Implications of Research in the Behavioral Sciences for Group Life and Group Services." In The Social Welfare Forum, 1960 "The Importance of Sequence in Teaching Reading." In Sequential Development of Reading Abilities "New Areas for Foundation Initiative." In Proceedings of the Conference of Foundations "Psychological Knowledge and Needed Curriculum Research." In Research Frontiers in the Study of Children’s Learning "Social Trends, and Problems for Tomorrow's Schools." In New Teaching Aids for the American Classroom "What We Think We Know About College Teaching and Learning." In Proceedings of the American Association of Land-Grant Colleges and State Universities (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - 1960, "What Testing Does to Teachers and Students." In Proceedings of the 1959 Invitational Conference on Testing Problems (Box 62, Folder 7)
    - 1961, "The Educational Potential of 4-H." In Selected Readings and References in 4-H Club Work "The Impact of Students on Schools and Colleges." In Social Forces Influencing American Education "Introduction to the Study; Conclusions and Recommendations." In Work-Study College Programs; Appraisal and Report of the Study of Cooperative Education "Mental Health and National Survival; Mr. Tyler's Analysis." In Official Report, American Association of School Administrators for the Year 1960-61 Preface to Evaluating Liberal Adult Education "The Purpose and Plan of This Yearbook." In Social Forces Influencing American Education "The Role and Responsibility of the College to Public Education." In Appropriate Directions for the Modern College in the Challenging New Educational Era "Social Forces Influencing American Education." In Unity in Diversity "Some Guiding Principles for Decision-Making." In Measurement and Research in Today's Schools "Trends in Interdisciplinary Research." In Trends in Social Science "Understanding Stability and Change in American Education." In Social Forces Influencing American Education The Values of Cooperative Education (Box 62, Folder 8)
    - 1961, Report on Cooperative Education (Box 62, Folder 9)
    - 1961, Building the Social Work Curriculum (Box 62, Folder 10)
    - 1962, "Applications of the Behavioral Sciences." In Teacher Education; A Reappraisal "The Curriculum in Higher Education." In Higher Education Tomorrow "The Evaluation of General Extension in Land-Grant Institutions." In Proceedings of the American Association of Land-Grant Colleges and State Universities. Vol. 2; 75th Annual Convention, Centennial Convocation Foreword to The Scholars Look at the Schools "The Worth of a Small Christian College." In Aurora College; A Dedication Record (Box 62, Folder 11)
    - 1962, Some Reflections on Soviet Education (Box 62, Folder 12)
    - 1963, "An Assessment; The Edge of the Future." In The Social Studies; Curriculum Proposals for the Future "The Behavioral Sciences and Education." In The 1963 Jennings Scholar Lectures "The Impact of External Testing Programs." In The Impact and Improvement of School Testing Programs "Programming of Science and Technology Within the Educational Structure." In Science, Technology, and Development. Vol. 11; Human Resources; Training of Scientific and Technical Personnel (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - 1963, "The Role of Machines in Educational Decision-Making." In Proceedings of the 1962 Invitational Conference on Testing Problems (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - 1963, "Social Change and College Admissions." In The Behavioral Sciences and Education "The Social or Behavioral Sciences." In Science in the College Curriculum "The Study of Campus Cultures." In The Study of Campus Cultures (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - 1964, "Future Prospects of the Behavioral Sciences." In The Behavioral Sciences; Problems and Prospects (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - 1964, "In-Service Training; Problems and Needs." In Proceedings; Region Six Conference on Planning In-Service Training Programs for Mental Health "National Planning and Quality Control in Education." In Modern Viewpoints in the Curriculum "Research on Academic Curriculum Innovations." In Research on Academic Curriculum Innovations "Some Persistent Questions on the Defining of Objectives." In Defining Educational Objectives The Foreign Student; Whom Shall We Welcome? (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - 1965, "The Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences; An Experiment." In The Creative Organization "Criteria for Evaluating Research." In Translating Research into Action "The Field of Educational Research." In The Training and Nurture of Educational Researchers "Innovations in Our Schools and Colleges." In White House Conference on Education; A Milestone for Educational Progress [Report of Vice Chairman for Panels on Innovations in Education.] In White House Conference on Education; A Milestone for Educational Progress "Sequences in Learning in Teacher Education." In Eighteenth Teacher Education Conference "Summary of Topic 6; What Is the Continuing Development of Occupation or Career After the Initial Commitment?" In Summarizers’ Reports of the Conference on Unexplored Aspects of the Development of Occupational Goals of Youth (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - 1966, "Analysis of Strengths and Weaknesses in Current Research in Science Education." In The Role of Centers for Science Education in the Production, Demonstration, and Dissemination of Research "Answers to Inquiries." In National Educational Assessment; Pro and Con "Assessing the Progress of Education." In Education and Social Change "The Behavioral Sciences and the Schools." In The Changing American School "Curriculum; Challenge for Experimentation." In Nursing Education; Creative, Continuing, Experimental (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - 1966, "The Development of Instruments for Assessing Educational Progress." In Proceedings of the 1965 Invitational Conference on Testing Problems (Box 63, Folder 8)
    - 1966, "Frontiers in Industrial Arts Education." In Frontiers in Industrial Arts Education "Resources, Models, and Theory in the Improvement of Research in Science Education." In The Role of Centers for Science Education in the Production, Demonstration, and Dissemination of Research "The Social Sciences; Major Problems and Challenges of the Future." In Expanding Horizons of Knowledge About Man "The Task Ahead." In National Conference on Education of the Disadvantaged "Values for a Changing America." In Values for a Changing America "What Is Evaluation?" In Reading; Seventy-five Years of Progress Dialogue on Out-of-Classroom Education "A Program of National Assessment." Address and Panel Reactions. In Official Report, American Association of School Administrators, 1965-66 (Box 63, Folder 9)
    - 1967, "An Overview of American Higher Education." In Higher Education in a Changing World "Changing Concepts of Educational Evaluation." In Perspectives of Curriculum Evaluation "Development of the National Assessment Project." In Improving Mathematics Education for Elementary School Teachers "The Educational Opportunity for the American College." In Thoughts About the Private Colleges "Hutchins, Robert Maynard." In Encyclopedia Britannica "The National Assessment of American Education." In Proceedings of the Summer Conference "Purposes, Scope and Organization of Education." In Implications for Education of Prospective Changes in Society + preprint Report of the Postdoctoral Educational Research Training Program of the Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences National Assessment of Educational Progress; Some Questions and Comments (Box 63, Folder 10)
    - 1968, The Challenge of National Assessment "Contributions of the Behavioral Sciences to Teacher Education." In Vocational-Technical Teacher Education Foreword to Picking Up the Options "Human Behavior in a Humanistic Curriculum." In Human Potential in a Dynamic Environment (Box 63, Folder 11)
    - 1968, "Investing in Better Schools." In Agenda for the Nation "New Directions in Individualizing Instruction." In The Abington Conference `67 on New Directions in Individualizing Instruction "The Rationale for Nationwide Assessment of Music Instruction." In Music in American Society; Documentary Report of the Tanglewood Symposium "The Role of Music in Our Philosophy of Education." In Music in American Society; Documentary Report of the Tanglewood Symposium What Is an Ideal Assessment Program? "What Price Quality in Education?" In The Unfinished Journey; Issues in American Education National Assessment of Educational Progress; Some Questions and Comments (Box 63, Folder 12)
    - 1969, "The Changing Structure of American Institutions of Higher Education." In The Economics and Financing of Higher Education in the United States "Charge to the Conference." In Teaching Psychiatry in Medical School "Education Must Relate to a Way of Life." In Automation and Society "Educational Effects of Examinations in the United States." In Examinations; The World Year Book of Education Foreword to Evaluation and the Work of the Teacher + Spanish translation Foreword to A Guide to Curriculum Construction for the Religious School Foreword to Research for Tomorrow's Schools "Impact of Testing on Student Development." In Impact of Testing on Student Development Introduction to Educational Evaluation; New Roles New Means (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - 1969, Introduction to National Assessment of Educational Progress [Citizenship, Science, Writing, Literature, Reading, Social Studies, Mathematics, Music, Art, Career and Occupational Development Objectives], 1969, 1970, 1971 (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - 1969, "Keynote Address; Symposium on Medical Education and Practice." In Medicine in the University and Community of the Future "The Learning Problems of The Young Adult." In The Young Adult "Outlook for the Future." In Educational Evaluation; New Roles, New Means "The Problems and Possibilities of Educational Evaluation." In The Schools and the Challenge of Innovation "The Purposes of Assessment." In Improving Educational Assessment and an of Measures of Affective Behavior "Statement by Ralph W. Tyler and Discussion." In Training Analysis; Report of the First Three-Institute Conference on Psychoanalytic Education (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - 1970, "Changing Responsibilities of Higher Education." In Academic Change and the Library Function "Epilogue; Academic Excellence and Equal Opportunity." In Issues of the Seventies; The Future of Higher Education Introduction to Every Kid a Winner; Accountability in Education "Schools for the 70's." In Individualized Curriculum and Instruction (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - 1971, "Accountability in Education; The Shift in Criteria." In Accountability in Education "Accountability in Perspective." In Accountability in Education (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - 1971, "The Concept of Functional Education." In Functional Education for Disadvantaged Youth "Concepts and the Teaching-Learning Process." In Selected Concepts from Educational Psychology and Adult Education for Extension and Continuing Educators "Curriculum Development in the Twenties and Thirties." In The Curriculum; Retrospect and Prospect "Education; Balancing Conditioned Response and Responsible Claims." In Environment and Society in Transition (Box 64, Folder 6)
    - 1971, Foreword to Children Teach Children; Learning by Teaching "In-Service Education of Teachers; A Look at the Past and Future." In Improving In-Service Education Introduction to Discrepancy Evaluation for Educational Program Improvement and Assessment "National Assessment; A History and Sociology." In New Models for American Education (Box 64, Folder 7)
    - 1971, "Report of the Ad hoc Committee on International Activities After the Gränna Seminar." In Report of the International Seminar for Advanced Training in Curriculum Development and Innovation (Box 64, Folder 8)
    - 1971, "Testing and Assessment Programs, National." In The Encyclopedia of Education "Values and Objectives." In Handbook of Cooperative Education A Viable Model for a College of Education (Box 64, Folder 9)
    - 1972, "Annual Report of the Acting President." In Social Science Research Council Annual Report, 1971-1972 Foreword to Colleges and the Urban Poor "More Effective Education for the Professions." In Human Resources and Economic Welfare "Summary of Conference." In Proceedings of the National Conference on Cooperative Education (Box 64, Folder 10)
    - 1973, "An Evaluation of Test Development Procedures Used and Implications for Curriculum Design." In A Structure of Concept Attainment Abilities "The Autonomous Teacher." In Facts and Feelings in the Classroom "Can a University Determine Its Future?" In Proceedings of the Higher Education Colloquium "E.F. Lindquist, Educational Pioneer." In Frontiers of Educational Measurement and Information Systems "Educational Evaluation in the Revolutionary Age." In Educational Communication in a Revolutionary Age The Future of the University; Stasis and Change (Box 64, Folder 11)
    - 1973, "How to Improve Instruction on the Basis of Evaluation." In Better Instruction Through Better Evaluation "Hutchins, Robert Maynard." In Encyclopedia Britannica "Keynote Address" and "Concluding Remarks." In Getting Research and Evaluation Underway at All Levels of Community Education Research in Science Teaching in a Larger Context "The Right Student, the Right Time, and the Right Place." In College/Career Choice "Schools for Young Children; The Recent American Past." In Education in Anticipation of Tomorrow "Evaluating the Effectiveness of a Foundation Grant." In Sharpening the Focus of Philanthropy (Box 64, Folder 12)
    - 1974, Educating Children of the Poor; 1975-1985 "Education; An Optimistic View." In Social Psychiatry Foreword to New Roles for Youth in the School and the Community Preface to Learning and Growing Through Tutoring "The Theoretical Phase of Psychoanalytic Education; Teaching and Learning." In Conference on Psychoanalytic Education and Research "The Use of Concepts in Developing a Curriculum." In The Concept Approach to Programming in Adult Education; With Special Application to Extension Education (Box 64, Folder 13)
    - 1974, Crucial Issues in Testing (Box 64, Folder 14)
    - 1974, Proceedings of the National Advisory Panel [on Career Education] (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - 1975, "Competency-Based Education; A Curriculum Point of View." In Competency-Based Education; Theory, Practice, Evaluation "Education of Children for Environmental and `Social' Awareness." In Environment and Society in Transition; World Priorities Foreword to Update on Education; A Digest of the National Assessment of Educational Progress "Historical Efforts to Develop Learning on a Competency Base." In A CBC Primer "Implications of the IEA Studies for Curriculum and Instruction; Commentary 2." In Educational Policy and International Assessment "Managing and Evaluating Innovative Programs." In Improving Education Through Project Management, Evaluation and Communication "Procedures for Implementing Curriculum Changes in Local Educational Agencies." In Improving Vocational Curricula in Local Education Agencies "The School of the Future; Needed Research and Development." In The Future of Education; Perspectives on Tomorrow's Schooling "Social Change and School Responsiveness." In School Reforms of the 1970's "Specific Approaches to Curriculum Development." In Strategies for Curriculum Development (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - 1976, The American Schools Can Meet the New Demands They Are Facing "An Overview of Basic Principles of Curriculum and Instruction." In Planning Curricula in Physical Therapy + reissue, 1982 "Assessing Needs and Determining Goals." In Proceedings; Conference on the Community/Junior College "The Competencies of Youth." In From School to Work; Improving the Transition "Dialogue." In The Student as Colleague; Medical Education Experience at Case Western Reserve Foreword to Reason and Art in Teaching Secondary-School English Introduction to Facing the Future; Issues in Education and Schooling (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - 1976, Facilitating Learning with Adults; What Ralph Tyler Says (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - 1976, Perspectives on American Education; Reflections on the Past...Challenges for the Future (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - 1976, Prospects for Research and Development in Education (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - 1976, "Rebuilding the Total Educational System." In Between Home and Community; Chronicle of the Francis W. Parker School, 1901-1976 Trends, Issues and New Directions in American Education." In Addresses and Interactions; Project 2000 Forum for Agricultural Education in Iowa + outline "Uses and Abuses of Testing." In Policy Issues in Education (Box 65, Folder 7)
    - 1977, "The Curricular Deliberation." In From the Scholar to the Classroom; Translating Jewish Tradition into Curriculum "Desirable Content for a Curriculum Development Syllabus Today." In Curriculum Theory Foreword to Curriculum Evaluation; Theory and Practice, with a Case Study from Nursing Education Foreword to A Theory of Education "Innovation and Productivity; Possibilities, Conflicts, and Resistance." In Innovation and Productivity in Higher Education Interview in Curriculum Change Toward the 21st Century "Planning, Development, and Coordination; Overview." In International Encyclopedia of Higher Education "The Total Educational Environment." In Education for Responsible Citizenship "What Have We Learned About Learning?" In Learning An Overview and Update Implications of American Democratic Civic Ethics for Schools (Box 65, Folder 8)
    - 1978, "Accountability and Teacher Performance." In The In-Service Education of Teachers "Comments." In Achievement Testing of Disadvantaged and Minority Students for Educational Program Evaluation (Box 65, Folder 9)
    - 1978, "Conserving Human Resources; The School Dropout." In From Youth to Constructive Adult Life; The Role of the Public School (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - 1978, "Education; Past, Present, and Future." In Educational Reform for a Changing Society "Educational Values of Cooperative Education." In Developing and Expanding Cooperative Education Foreword to Curriculum for Better Schools; The Great Ideological Debate Foreword to The State of Teacher Education, 1977 "The Future of American Education." In Focus on the Future; Implications for Education "Historical Perspective on the Role of the Parents in Education." In Whose Child Is This? (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - 1978, "How Schools Utilize Educational Research and Development." In Research and Development and School Change (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - 1978, "A New Kind of Curriculum for the New Times." In Perspectives on Improving Education; Project Talent's Young Adults Look Back "A Statement from the ACT Board of Trustees." In The American College Testing Program Annual Report, 1978 "What the Curriculum Field Needs to Learn from Its History." In What the Curriculum Field Needs to Learn from Its History The Florida Accountability Program; An Evaluation of Its Educational Soundness and Implementation (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - 1979, "An Advanced Study Center for Vocational Education; Goals and Challenges." In Advanced Study Center; Proceedings of the National Faculty Plenary Conference (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - 1979, "Conclusions." In China's Schools in Flux (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - 1979, "Curriculum Planning in Vocational Education." In Vocational Instruction "Educating Children Democratically." In Educating All Our Children; An Imperative for Democracy "Educational Improvements Best Served by Curriculum Development." In Value Conflicts and Curriculum Issues; Lessons from Research and Experience (Box 66, Folder 7)
    - 1979, "Educational Objectives and Educational Testing; Problems Now Faced." In Testing, Teaching and Learning Foreword to The Skills of Teaching "A Message from the Board of Trustees." In The American College Testing Program Annual Report, 1979 "Teacher Education and the Improvement of Instruction." In Teacher Education and National Development "Chairmen's Preface" and "Chairmen's Report." In Testing, Teaching and Learning + pamphlet edition (Box 66, Folder 8)
    - 1980, "Achievement Testing and the Publisher." In Proceedings, The Third National Conference on Testing; Uniting Testing and Teaching Educational Evaluation; A Retrospective View "Educational Technology; Influence and Future." In Educational Media Yearbook 1980 If Not I.Q., What? "The Management of Educational Decline." In Critical Issues in Educational Policy; An Administrator's Overview "The Needs of Elementary and Secondary Education for the 1980's." In Needs of Elementary and Secondary Education in the 1980's; A Compendium of Policy Papers "Parental Involvement in Curriculum Decision-making; A Review and Critique." In A Two-Way Street; Home-School Cooperation in Curriculum Decision making "Reactors Comments and Concluding Remarks." In The Role of Education in the Re-Industrialization of the United States Role of Assessment Information in Improving Educational Programs "Three Major Movements; As Viewed from Three Perspectives." In Measuring Achievement; Progress Over a Decade (Box 66, Folder 9)
    - 1981, An Interview with Ralph Tyler "Challenges for Teaching." In The Future of Education; Policy Issues and Challenges Foreword to Testing in the States; Beyond Accountability "Rebuilding the Total Educational System." In Schooling and Society "Remarks." In The Parent Participation TV Workshop Project Manual (Box 66, Folder 10)
    - 1981, "Societal Expectations for the American School; A Long View." In Education in the 80's; Curricular Challenges "Testimony of Ralph Tyler." In Minimum Competency Testing Clarification Hearing, July 8, 1981 "The Values of Cooperative Education from a Pedagogical Perspective." In A Strategy for the Development of Human and Economic Resources "What Is Affective Education and How Do We Bring It About?" In Children and Our Future (Box 66, Folder 11)
    - 1982, "Integrated Research, Development, Dissemination and Practice in Science Education." In Proceedings; Project Directors Meeting + ERIC paper (Box 66, Folder 12)
    - 1983, "The Meaning of Community Education; An Historical Perspective." In For Every School a Community; Expanding Environments for Learning (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - 1983, Preface to Philosophy for Education (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - 1983, "A Rationale for Program Evaluation." In Evaluation Models; Viewpoints on Educational and Human Services Evaluation The Tasks of UCEA for the '80's [University Council for Educational Administration] "Testing Writing; Procedures Vary with Purposes." In Literacy for Life; The Demand for Reading and Writing "Goals and Objectives." In Fundamental Curriculum Decisions (Box 67, Folder 3)